Guide to the Gerard Malanga Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Gerard Malanga Papers
1906-2008
1970-2006
YCAL MSS 813
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
104.78
(140 boxes) + 3 art, 6 rolls, 7 broadside folders
The collection contains materials documenting the artistic, professional, and personal activities of Gerard Malanga. Materials include correspondence, research and subject files, drafts and printed versions of writings, photographic materials, audiovisual materials, printed materials, and artwork. There is correspondence with publishers and editors, galleries and cultural organizations, writers, friends, and family. The research files and writings document work by Malanga and others. There are drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, of a great many individual poems by Malanga and more extensive, though scattered files for collections of poems and other book-length projects, such as Ten Years After (1977), This Will Kill That (1983), Mythologies of the Heart (1996), and Scopophilia (1985). Materials can also be found for projects that relate to Malanga's work as a photograph archivist for the New York City Parks Department, including books on Robert Moses and public swimming facilities in the city. Photographic materials include negatives, contact sheets, and prints, and feature portraits of writers and artists, chiefly American poets, dating from the late 1960s and early 1970s. Audiovisual materials include audiocassettes, reel-to-reel sound recordings, and optical media, including readings and performances by Malanga and others. Printed materials include posters, issues of magazines, clippings, and ephemera.
Malanga, Gerard, 1943-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 113-117, 119, and 154-155 (Audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Photo Anonyme Ltd. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund and gift of Asako Kitaori and Gerard Malanga, 2006-2009.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into six groupings: I. September 2006 Acquisition. II. September 2006 Addition. III. November 2007 Acquisition. IV. November 2007 Addition. V. July 2008 Acquisition. VI. September 2009 Acquisition.
Gerard Malanga (1943-)
Gerard Malanga is an American poet, photographer, and filmmaker. He was born in New York in 1943 and studied at the School of Industrial Art and Wagner College. He was Andy Warhol's chief assistant from 1963 to 1970 and, in addition to starring in many of Warhol's early films, he also made and starred in films of his own. His books of poetry include This Will Kill That (1978) and Mythologies of the Heart (1996), and his books of photography include Good Girls (1994) and Resistance to Memory (1998). He also edited a book on voyeurism in photography entitled Scopophilia: The Love of Looking (1985). Malanga lives and works in New York.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains materials documenting the artistic, professional, and personal activities of Gerard Malanga. Materials include correspondence, research and subject files, drafts and printed versions of writings, photographic materials, audiovisual materials, printed materials, and artwork. There is correspondence with publishers and editors, galleries and cultural organizations, writers, friends, and family. The research files and writings document work by Malanga and others. There are drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, of a great many individual poems by Malanga and more extensive, though scattered files for collections of poems and other book-length projects, such as Ten Years After (1977), This Will Kill That (1983), Mythologies of the Heart (1996), and Scopophilia (1985). Materials can also be found for projects that relate to Malanga's work as a photo archivist for the New York City Parks Department, including books on Robert Moses and public swimming facilities in the city. Photographic materials include negatives, contact sheets, and prints, and feature portraits of writers and artists, chiefly American poets, dating from the late 1960s and early 1970s. Audiovisual materials include audiocassettes, reel-to-reel sound recordings, and optical media, including readings and performances by Malanga and others. Printed materials include posters, issues of magazines, clippings, and ephemera.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Photography, Artistic; Photographers -- United States; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Photographic prints; Posters; Sound recordings; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographers -- United States -- 20th Century; Malanga, Gerard, 1943-; Moses, Robert, 1888-1981; Warhol, Andy, 1928-1987; New York (N.Y.). Department of Parks
- September 2006 acquisition, 1906-2005; 81.05; (102 boxes) + 2 art, 6 rolls, 4 broadside folders
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Photo Anonyme Ltd. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2006.
  Scope and Contents
  The first September 2006 Acquisition contains material documenting the artistic, professional, and personal activities of Gerard Malanga. Materials include correspondence, research and subject files, drafts and printed versions of writings, photographs, artwork, audiovisual materials, and printed materials, including posters, issues of magazines, clippings, and ephemera.
  In the contents list below, folder titles transcribed from those provided by the creator or previous custodian are indicated by quotations marks.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 898.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 113-114 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Arrangement
  Material has been left in the order in which it was received by the library.
  - "Correspondence ca. 1998", 1996-1999, undated; 6 (Box 1)
  - "2nd Poetry Blitz Starting 2:ix:97", 1997-1998, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - "1998 - 1st Poetry Blitz", 1997-1999, undated; 3 (Box 1)
  - "Blitz Starting November 4, 1998", 1998-1999, undated; 4 (Box 2)
  - "S. Kay Young - Assorted Photos", 1988, undated (Box 2)
  - Poetry, 1995-1999, undated; 3 (Box 2)
  - Brochures, 1991-2000, undated (Box 2)
  - "Gerard's Filmscript", 1993-1999, undated (Box 2)
  - "Cinema Parlant. Scenario Original de Gerard Malanga", 1993 (Box 2)
  - "Pictures from Memory", 1985, undated (Box 2)
  - "S. R. Lavin", 1998, undated (Box 2)
  - "'You're It,' Final Drafts", undated (Box 2)
  - "'Bosnia,' Poem", 1995, undated (Box 2)
  - "GM: Fly[e]rs", 1987-1988, undated (Box 2)
  - "Rolling Stone Solicitation of Gerard's Folios", 1963-1987 (Box 2)
  - "Pictures from Memory / Draft by Gerard Malanga", undated (Box 2)
  - "GM: This Photograph Is 25-years into the Future Now (1985)" (Box 2)
  - "Draft of Poem, 'This Is a Photo of You...' 1983" (Box 2)
  - "Dustin Pittman, Gerard's Friend with Whom He Assisted in the Early 1980s", undated (Box 2)
  - "Light Work", 1984, undated (Box 2)
  - "A. D. Coleman Article...", undated (Box 2)
  - "Piero Heliczer Poem ca. Late 1950s", undated (Box 2)
  - "GM: Camera Mag. Article by Peter Wehrli, ca. Early 1980s", undated (Box 2)
  - "GM Exhibit: The Cooper Union, ca. 1984", undated (Box 2)
  - "GM Exhibit: Gotham Book Mart Gallery - 1974", 1974 November (Box 2)
  - "GM Exhibit: Usdan Gallery - Bennington College - 1980", 1980 July (Box 2)
  - "1st Poetry Blitz - 6:iii:97", 1993-1998, undated; 6 (Box 2)
  - "GM: Film Programme, ca. 1976", undated (Box 2)
  - "Photo Text Plaque by Gerard Malanga", undated (Box 2)
  - "Positively Archival, Master Copy 1988", 1988 January 12 (Box 2)
  - "Notes on Photography", 1984-1990, undated (Box 2)
  - "GM: After Dark Mag. Feature - 1976", 1976 September 9 (Box 2)
  - "GM Interview Portrait:Theory (Lustrum Press)", undated (Box 2)
  - "Ma[r?]kers. Feltrinelli Poem 'Prototypes of Experience'", 1980 June 18 (Box 2)
  - "Pictures from Memory, Drafts", undated (Box 3)
  - Poetry, 1964-1999, undated; 7 (Box 3)
  - "Notes Towards Introductory Essay on Photography by Gerard Malanga", 1983-1995, undated (Box 3)
  - "What Can I Tell You About Myself", 1992 (Box 3)
  - "Aram Saroyan Essay on Gerard's Photography", undated (Box 3)
  - "'The Things We Do for England,' Poetry Bk Mss by Malanga", 1971-1992, undated (Box 3)
  - "Original Typescripts / G. Malanga", 1977-1979 (Box 3)
  - "Drafts by Gerard Malanga", 1982-1992, undated (Box 3)
  - "GM: Typescripts of Poems", 1995-1999 (Box 3)
  - "Book Review (Unpublished) by Gerard Malanga", undated (Box 3)
  - "Andy Warhol Film Project / Working File. Gerard Malanga - Jim Clyne, Producers", 1988-1992; 2 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 3)
  - "Photocopy Enlargement Concepts", undated (Box 3)
  - "Ellie Brooks", 1971-1981 (Box 3)
  - "N.E.A. Note Fragments", 1986, undated (Box 3)
  - "LINE FDN Grant Application", 1984, undated (Box 3)
  - "GM: Flyers / Ads / Announcements", 1994-1996, undated (Box 3)
  - "GM: Unemployment Records re. Vrej Baghoomian Gallery", 1987-1989, undated (Box 3)
  - "Correspondence: Gerard's Picture Book", 1993 December 9 (Box 3)
  - "Dreams / Drafts & Final Texts", 1989-1995 (Box 3)
  - "Tina Modotti, Photographer", 1977-1995 (Box 3)
  - "Dominique Clavreul / Evidence / Nantes, FR", 1980-1996 (Box 3)
  - "Copies of Correspondence", 1976-1986 (Box 3)
  - "Don Snyder, Alchemist Photographer + GM's Photo Mentor", 1986-1995; 2 (Box 4)
  - "Tracy M. Lippard, Beauty Queen", 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - "Alajos Schuszler Tearsheets in Writing Article", 1937-1985, undated (Box 4)
  - "Poetry Blitz Listings", undated (Box 4)
  - "U.S. Passport Application", 1993, undated (Box 4)
  - "Viages Photo Agency / Marysa Maslansky", undated (Box 4)
  - "'Out of the Body, in the Nude,' by Gerard Malanga", undated (Box 4)
  - "'What This Poem Is Not About,' by Gerard Malanga", 1993, undated (Box 4)
  - "Gerard Malanga Sketch", 1980 (Box 4)
  - "Paris Correspondence", 1994-1996, undated (Box 4)
  - "Articles on Gerard Malanga", 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - "Draft to a Poem Written in Paris", 1992 (Box 4)
  - "Gia Carangi / Contact Sheets", 1993, undated (Box 4)
  - "Portraits of Gerard Malanga in the Berkshires by Robert Shapiro ca. 1991", undated (Box 4)
  - "Gregory Corso / Research for Interview that Never Happened", 1969-1980, undated (Box 4)
  - "Interview Questions / Drafts", undated (Box 4)
  - "Sarah Greenleaf Whittier", 1983-1989 (Box 4)
  - "Aleson South", undated (Box 4)
  - "Robert Shapazian re 'Toward the Roots of Surrealism: Homage to Freud'", 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - "Notes from Gravity & Grace, Simone Weil", undated (Box 4)
  - "Kathy Acker Research into Request for Photo of Author by Gerard Malanga", undated (Box 4)
  - "Olga Peters / Svetlana", 1984-1985, undated (Box 4)
  - "The Most Beautiful Girl in the World 40x60 Approx.", undated (Box 4)
  - "Richard Aaron / Henry Moore", 1980-1982, undated; (2 folders, 1 audiocassette) (Box 4)
    The audiocassette is stored in box 113 under the title: Henry Moore/Richard Aaron.
  - "GM Responses", 1980-1982 (Box 4)
  - "Requests", 1979-1986, undated (Box 4)
  - "Gerard Malanga Ephemera", 1974-1988 (Box 4)
  - "Postcards", 1968-1986, undated (Box 4)
  - "Miscellany", 1980-1986 (Box 4)
  - "Correspondence of Noted + / or Correspondence from Noted Photographers", 1966-1975, undated (Box 4)
  - "Correspondence Legal Size", 1974-1989; 3 (Box 4)
  - "Maxwell Mackenzie", 1978-1979, undated (Box 5)
  - "Drafts of Texts. Warhol Exhibition", 1988-1989, undated (Box 5)
  - "Dia Art FDN", 1988, undated (Box 5)
  - "Gerard Malanga: Loans Correspondence", 1988 (Box 5)
  - "Miscellaneous", 1962, undated (Box 5)
  - "Receipts", 1988 March (Box 5)
  - "Correspondence: Emile de Antonio, Peter Wehrli, Baird Jones", 1988 (Box 5)
  - "Tearsheets + Photocopies", 1988 (Box 5)
  - "Andy Warhol: Genesis of an Installation", 1988 (Box 5)
  - "John Hanardt / Whitney Museum of American Art", 1988 (Box 5)
  - "Photocopies-Warhol's Art", 1988 April (Box 5)
  - "Correspondence / Floor Plan / Checklist Chart", 1988, undated (Box 5)
  - "Andy Warhol: Genesis of an Installation. Catalog + Fax Set of Texts", 1988, undated (Box 5)
  - "Drafts-Andy Warhol: After Photography (Text for Catalog) by Gerard Malanga", 1988, undated (Box 5)
  - "Specimens: Photo Invitation, Art Review (Barnard Bulletin), Press Release", 1988 (Box 5)
  - "Loan Agreement Forms", 1988 (Box 5)
  - "1st Draft Delineation for Catalog", undated (Box 5)
  - "Proofs of Color Plates", 1988 November (Box 5)
  - "Photography Related Letters, Post Cards & Miscellany", 1970-1985 (Box 5)
  - "Photography Related Letter-size Correspondence", 1966-1986, undated (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1988; 2 (Box 5)
  - "John + Vicky Perkins", 1981-1987, undated (Box 5)
  - " Scopophilia, Supplementary File", 1982-1986 (Box 5)
  - "Karen Bjornson", 1976 (Box 5)
  - "Extended Correspondence Poetry + Photography", 1975-1986 (Box 5)
  - "Units of Correspondents. Poetry + Photography", 1970-1988, undated (Box 5)
  - "Poets & Writers A to Z File" (A-E), 1975-1992, undated (Box 6)
  - "Poets & Writers A to Z File" (G-L), 1974-1986, undated (Box 6)
  - "Poets & Writers A to Z File" (M-O), 1974-1986, undated (Box 6)
  - "Poets & Writers A to Z File" (P-R), 1974-1984, undated (Box 6)
  - "Poets & Writers A to Z File" (S-T), 1966-1985, undated (Box 6)
  - "Poets & Writers A to Z File" (W-Z), 1970-1986, undated (Box 6)
  - "Postcards", 1906-1984; 4 (Box 6)
  - "Priority Correspondence", 1997-2000; 5 (Box 6)
  - "Ira Cohen: Correspondence & Ephemera", 1982-1995, undated; 8 (Box 7)
  - "Ira Cohen Ephemera, etc.", undated (Box 7)
  - "Ira Cohen Interview, 8:ii:96 NYC w/ Gerard Malanga", 1996 February 8 (Box 7)
  - "Script, Holographs & Working Drafts", undated; 3 (Box 7)
  - "Completed Scenes, Revised 1st Draft", 1993, undated (Box 7)
  - "First 1/2 of File #1 Proofed + Corrected", undated (Box 7)
  - "Music", undated (Box 7)
  - "Typeset Original Draft", undated (Box 7)
  - "Interview with Greta Scacchi", undated (Box 8)
  - "Greta Scacchi", 1993, undated (Box 8)
  - "Notes Toward Working-Draft. Fly-fishing Concept", undated (Box 8)
  - "Shots & Tableaus To Be Developed", undated (Box 8)
  - "Cinema Parlant ('Talking Pictures') Written & Directed by Gerard Malanga. Master Copy-1st Complete Working Draft. Prepared on 19: viii:93. Completed Typing-12:x:93", 1993, undated (Box 8)
  - "Sequence: Chateau de Roussillion", undated (Box 8)
  - "A Catalogue of Jokes for Script", undated (Box 8)
  - "Horse Racing Episode", undated (Box 8)
  - "Expenses Incurred thru Research", 1993-1995 (Box 8)
  - "Film Production Financing", 1993-1995, undated (Box 8)
  - "Receipt Records of Script Copy Holders", 1993-1995, undated (Box 8)
  - "Music Soundtrack / Blocking Music for Shots", 1993 (Box 8)
  - "U.S. Postal Copyright Citation on 1st Clean Draft of Cinema Parlant ('Talking Pictures')" (empty), undated (Box 8)
  - "Master Copy-Cinema Parlant", 1993 (Box 8)
  - "The Merchant and Ivory Foundation Submission: 'Talking Pictures' as Work-in-Progress", 1993, undated (Box 8)
  - Copyright Office-Library of Congress, 1993 September (Box 8)
  - "Cinema Parlant ('Talking Pictures') Written & Directed by Gerard Malanga. First, Clean Draft of First 51-pgs. 19:viii:93", 1993 August (Box 8)
  - "Filmscript-French Trans", undated (Box 8)
  - "'Cinema Parlant' / Correspondence...", 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - "Casting, etc.", 1993 (Box 8)
  - "Location Research", 1990-1993, undated; 2 (Box 8)
  - "Ephemera", 1993, undated (Box 8)
  - "Papers To Be Integrated into Other Files", 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - "G.M. Texas A&M University Gallery 1979", 1975-1979 (Box 8)
  - "A Winter Lion / Jon Alexander. Gerard Stodolski...", 1980, undated (Box 8)
  - " The Coldspring Journal / Texts for Paste-Ups", 1979-1980, undated (Box 8)
  - " The Coldspring Journal #12", 1973-1975, undated (Box 8)
  - "Chelsea Hotel Magazine, Germany", 1982-1995 (Box 8)
  - "Dirk Gortler, Ed / Chelsea Hotel Mag", 1994-1998, undated (Box 8)
  - "U.S. Poetry Bookings", 1994, undated (Box 8)
  - "Book Publishing Deals", 1994-1995, undated (Box 8)
  - "Typed Notes for Eventual Cut-up", undated (Box 8)
  - " Grand Street, December 1997 issue" (Box 9)
  - "'Gerard Malanga Responds to a Poem by Max Blagg,' Working Drafts, 10:VII:98", 1998 (Box 9)
  - "'Gossip' / A Poem, 6/29/98", undated (Box 9)
  - "'Gossip' or 'The Tyranny of Poetry,' Working Drafts (1997)", 1997, undated (Box 9)
  - "Diana, Princess of Wales, Poem", 1997 (Box 9)
  - "Alessandra Bergero. Comune di Finale Ligure Assessorato Cultura, Italy", 1994-1998 (Box 9)
  - " Village Voice / Letter to the Editor re Marcel Duchamp Screen Test (1966)", 1995, undated (Box 9)
  - "Gordon Helman Working Drafts", 1996 (Box 9)
  - "'The Street' Working Drafts. Poem by Gerard Malanga, 1998", 1998 February (Box 9)
  - "'Cafe Gitane' (Working Drafts) 1998 Poem by Gerard Malanga", 1998, undated (Box 9)
  - "'Performance Art,' Working Drafts, 31:I:98", undated (Box 9)
  - "'The Council Flats,' Poem. 1997 Working Drafts" (Box 9)
  - "'Darcey Steinke Wears Calvin Klein Opp. Page' (1997) Working Drafts" (Box 9)
  - "'Have a Look,' Working Drafts, 8:VII:98", 1998 July (Box 9)
  - "Cheryl Chase, Pres. I.S.N.A.", 1984-1998, undated (Box 9)
  - "Rolf Vasellari", 1993-1998, undated (Box 9)
  - "Agatha Gaillard Galerie. 3, rue du Pont Louis Phillipe 75004 Paris, France", 1997 April 4 (Box 9)
  - "Ralph Gibson Text Project - 1997...", 1997 September 15 (Box 9)
  - "Paul W. Carman", 1998, undated (Box 9)
  - "Nexus / Larry Sawyer, Editor", 1989-1998 (Box 9)
  - "Henry J. Stern, Parks Commissioner", 1997 (Box 9)
  - "Salvidor Dali Bio / Faber & Faber", 1991-1997 (Box 9)
  - "Nantes, Fr. The Mayor's Office. M.Y. Guin, Development Council", 1997-1998; 2 (Box 9)
  - "Magazine Blitz - First Series. Literary Magazine Unsolicited Mss. Mail Blitz", 1994 (Box 9)
  - "Magazine Blitz - 2nd Series. Poetry Magazine Submissions - 2nd Series", 1994, undated (Box 9)
  - "Magazine Blitz - 3rd Series - Literary Magazines", 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - "4th Poetry Blitz", 1995 (Box 9)
  - "5th Poetry Blitz", 1995 (Box 9)
  - "The 6th Poetry Blitz", 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - "7th Poetry Blitz", 1995 (Box 9)
  - "8th Poetry Blitz", 1995 (Box 9)
  - "9th Poetry Blitz for October 1995", 1995-1996, undated (Box 9)
  - "10th Poetry Blitz", 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - "11th Poetry Blitz", 1996 (Box 9)
  - "A Purchase in the White Botanica: The Collected Poetry of Piero Heliczer", 1958-1969 (Box 9)
  - "Piero Heliczer Obit / Poetry Project Newsletter ", 1994 February (Box 9)
  - Piero Heliczer poems, undated (Box 9)
  - "Piero Heliczer Explains His Intentions in Applying for a Guggenheim Grant", 1977 (Box 10)
  - "1st Draft, 'No Respect / Selected Poems,' 25: VIII:99", 1964-1999; 3 (Box 10)
  - Piero Heliczer poetry and interview, undated (Box 10)
  - "A Purchase in the White Botanica," book jacket, undated (Box 10)
  - "Black Sparrow Press / GM Selected Poems", 2000-2001, undated; 11 (Box 10)
  - "'Uptight: The Velvet Underground Story,' Legal Papers...", 1982-1986, undated (Box 10)
  - "Friends", 1977-1987; 2 (Box 10)
  - "Publishers & Editors", 1966-1988 (Box 11)
  - "Tom Weigel", 1986 (Box 11)
  - "Fugitive Working Drafts-Gerard Malanga", 1980-1986 (Box 1)
  - "Flying Fuck", 1982-1984, undated (Box 11)
  - "Barry Savenor Mss for 'Indoor Life' by Malanga", 1986 (Box 11)
  - "Charles McGeehan", undated (Box 11)
  - "Lita Hornick", 1975-1988 (Box 11)
  - "Anjani Shah", 1987, undated (Box 11)
  - "Leslie Ullman", 1979-1981 (Box 11)
  - "Jean Stein", 1965-1986 (Box 11)
  - "Luann Rolley...", 1981, undate (Box 11)
  - " Chelsea #39 - Multi-media Issue", 1980, undated (Box 11)
  - "Aram Saroyan", 1975-1988, undated (Box 11)
  - "Poetry Reading Solicitations. 1974", 1973-1974, undated (Box 11)
  - " Little Caesar #9 Mss and Letters, etc.", 1979, undated (Box 11)
  - "Kathleen Norris", 1976-1986, undated (Box 11)
  - "Gerard Malanga Intro to Little Caesar #9", undated (Box 11)
  - "Michael Kohler / S Press Tapes", 1978-1980 (Box 11)
  - "Narcisa Hirsch", 1981-1982, undated (Box 11)
  - "'To a Young Girl in the Subway,' Isha Manna Beck", 1985, undated (Box 11)
  - "'Where To Begin?' Aleson South", 1973-1985, undated (Box 11)
  - "Broadcast / The Cure", 1983, undated (Box 11)
  - "Two or Three Things I Know About Her", 1986, undated (Box 11)
  - "Suddenly Next Summer", 1982, undated (Box 11)
  - "George Andrews - Poems", undated (Box 11)
  - "Daniel Cassidy, Jr. - Poems", undated (Box 11)
  - "The Ant's Forefoot #6 (Not Used)", 1970, undated (Box 11)
  - "Malanga / SOME Interview", undated (Box 11)
  - "Simon Vinkenoog and the Proust Questionaire", 1979 (Box 11)
  - "Gerard Malanga / Interview for The Helen Review ", undated (Box 11)
  - "Tom Peterson", 1978-1980, undated (Box 11)
  - "Interview w/ Gerard Malanga by Vicki Hudspith", undated (Box 11)
  - "Malanga / Gravida Interview", undated (Box 11)
  - "Notes for Poems", 1977-1979, undated (Box 11)
  - "Sunny Redmond", 1976 November 29 (Box 11)
  - "Michael Waters - Salisbury State College", 1984-1986, undated (Box 11)
  - "David Shapiro", 1962-1963 (Box 11)
  - "Gerard's Top Twenty", 1962-1968, undated (Box 11)
  - "Adrian Brooks - Lawsuit", 1981, undated (Box 11)
  - "Sotere Torregian", undated (Box 11)
  - "J. Rutherford Willems, Poet", 1974-1976 (Box 11)
  - "Sandra Sharpe", undated (Box 12)
  - "Collaborations: Andrei Codrescu Reads MacAdams and Gerard Malanga", 1970 (Box 12)
  - "Daniel Cassidy, Jr.", 1965 (Box 12)
  - "Frank Lima - Poems", undated (Box 12)
  - "Larry Mellman", 1971, undated (Box 12)
  - "Larry Mellman 'Yes America' (1966)" (Box 12)
  - " Coldspring Journal Poetry Mss. Bernadette Mayer", undated (Box 12)
  - " Coldspring Journal ", 1973-1979, undated (Box 12)
  - "Stephen Sandy", undated (Box 12)
  - "Bill Knott", 1968, undated (Box 12)
  - "Barbara Astman", 1978-1981, undated (Box 12)
  - "Joan Redmond", 1975-1982 (Box 12)
  - "Gerard Malanga - Paris Review Competition for the Long Poem", undated (Box 12)
  - "Dracula - Codrescu", 1974, undated (Box 12)
  - "Everson Museum of Art Ron Cook, Dir.", 1975-1976, undated (Box 12)
  - "Kevin Jeffrey Clarke, Bk Mss. - Poems", 1980 (Box 12)
  - "'The Children,' a Film by Gerard Malanga. Receipts, Correspondence, Synopsis, etc.", 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - "Camera - Lucerne, Switzerland", 1980 (Box 12)
  - "New American Nudes Competition", 1980 (Box 12)
  - "Kiva Gallery / John Carpenter", 1978 (Box 12)
  - "Mark Saunders / Sayres Path Mss", undated (Box 12)
  - "Gerard Malanga / Bikini Girl. Interview", 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - "Kestner - Gesellschaft. Andy Warhol Exhibition", 1981 (Box 12)
  - "Portrait: Theory", 1980, undated (Box 12)
  - "Michael Cooper", 1980, undated (Box 12)
  - "Jackson Mac Low / Dance", 1964, 1972 (Box 12)
  - "Erick Hawkins", undated (Box 12)
  - "An Early Essay by GM, ca. 1960", 1961 (Box 12)
  - "Stephen Sandy, 'Freestone'", undated (Box 12)
  - "Jonathan Kundra", undated (Box 12)
  - "Daniel Cassidy, Jr.", undated (Box 12)
  - "Poem Collaboration by Ted Berrigan + Ron Padgett", undated (Box 12)
  - "Bill Knott - MSS", undated (Box 12)
  - "Gerard Malanga Reviews. Daniel Halpern for Poetry", 1974-1975 (Box 12)
  - "Resumes / Dobs, etc.", 1975-1985, undated (Box 12)
  - "Photo Exhibit Flyers", 1980-1986 (Box 12)
  - "Herald Poetry Column / Shelley Lustig", 1971 (Box 12)
  - "Gerard Malanga Monograph Proposed by W. W. Norton", 1986, undated (Box 12)
  - "Real Art Ways", 1979 (Box 12)
  - "Pornography Copy / Luann Photo", undated (Box 12)
  - "Malanga's Top Twenty", undated (Box 12)
  - "Alwin Nikolais", 1956-1962, undated (Box 12)
  - " This Will Kill That - Final Typescript Draft", 1983 (Box 12)